（モブ）
わあ～ 待て 待て～！
Wait! Wait!
Hey, now! You're going to fall
if you keep running like that!
（モブの母）
ほらほら
そんなに走ったら危ないわ！
Are you okay, Onii-chan?
（影山(かげやま) 律(りつ)）
お兄ちゃん 大丈夫？
（母）
もう
だから危ないって言ったのに…
See? I told you.
Come on, let me see.
ほら 見せてごらん
うわ～ん！
わあ…
あっ ちょっとシゲ やめなさい！
Shige! Stop that!
（モブの父）
ハハハ 何だ こりゃ？
What the heck?
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Coming down, could you fill your satisfaction?
You're a MOB. Can't you feel your own frustration?
You're a MOB. What do you want to be?
Wear your overflowing emotions on your sleeve and break it down
What do you see once you go beyond your limits?
(99.9! 99.9!)
The mysterious percentage.
Cryin' my life, cryin' my psyche,
cryin' my heart in such commonplaces!
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind?
It all begins when it hits 100.
The MOB is alive. The MOB is high.
The MOB is staying frustrated, aren't you?
Is that your ideal? Is that your mind? Right now...
Your life is your own.
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
Mob Psycho
(Get ready, dig your anger up, MOB!)
(Get ready, wake your psyche up, MOB!)
(Get ready!)
Even Then
~Continue Forward~
Now Mob-kun even has a building in his name.
（米里(めざと)イチ）
ついにビルまで
所有しちゃったわね モブ君
Psycho Helmet Religion
Even though the Psycho Helmet Religion
has yet to find its leader,
（米里）
サイコヘルメット教は
教祖不在のまま 信者700人を突破
it now has over 700 members.
Psycho Helmet Religion
Due to an anonymous donation,
they were able to create a headquarters
匿名の寄付のおかげで
拠点のビルを手に入れ
and its followers are working hard,
day after day, to recruit more followers.
信者たちは
日夜 布教活動に励んでいる
They have no form of scripture
nor really any idea what to do.
経典もなく
具体的に何をどうすればいいか
分からないまま
All they know is that their beloved founder
is apparently a real esper
とりあえず
教祖が本物の超能力者で
and in middle school.
中学生らしいというだけで
Psycho Helmet Religion
ネットにもネタ宗教として
The religion is also gaining popularity
and spreading on the internet
as a meme religion.
話題が拡散され始めている
If Mob-kun finally appears,
this order will get even bigger.
モブ君が現れれば この集団は
更に大きな熱を帯びることになる
I want to see it happen!
見届けたい！
Because... It seems like it'd be fun.
だって 面白そうなんだもん
It's finally that time of year again.
（古賀(こが)先生）
え～ ついに
この時期がやって来たぞ
The annual marathon is here.
毎年恒例のマラソン大会だ
In 10 days
Salt Middle School All-Student
Marathon Contest
（男子生徒たち）
キタ～！　マジかよ～
Seriously?
No way! We have to run 5 kilometers again?
（古賀）仮病しないように！
（男子生徒）ヤダよ～　５キロも―
Don't even try faking any sickness.
I'll see right through it!
（古賀）先生 見抜くからな
（男子生徒）走らされるのかよ
Mob-kun.
（米里）
モブ君
Mezato-san? What is it?
（モブ）
米里さん 何？
There's something I want to talk to you about.
ちょっと相談したいことがあって
Could you come to the roof during lunch?
昼休みに屋上まで来てくれない？
It's really important.
すごく大事な話
Middle School Math
I'll be waiting for you.
じゃあ 待ってるから
Shigeo...
（エクボ）
茂夫(しげお)
Maybe you're going to get asked out again!
お前 また告白されんじゃねえの？
For real this time!
今度はマジで！
No, I'm sure she just wants to talk.
（モブ）
いや 普通に相談でしょ
You're too dramatic, Dimple.
エクボは いちいち大げさなんだよ
Lame! What happened to
that innocent boy I used to know?
つまんねえ
変わっちまったな お前
Just the other day, you'd get beet red
and flustered simply from talking to a girl.
ちょっと前までは 女と話すだけで
顔 真っ赤にして
オロオロしてたのによ～！
You see, Mob-kun...
（米里）
あのね モブ君
About the marathon...
マラソン大会のことなんだけど
O-Oh, okay. It's about the marathon...
あ… はい
マラソン大会のことなんだ？
What? Was he actually expecting more?
（エクボ）
あれ？
こいつ 本当は期待してたんじゃ？
Why don't you use your powers
超能力とか使ってさ
to win by a landslide and surprise
the heck out of all the people watching?
ぶっちぎりの１位で
集った見物客を驚かせてみない？
Why would I do that?
（モブ）
なんで？
（米里）
実は ずっとモブ君を捜している
ファン集団がいるの
Well, there's this fan club
that's been looking for you.
ファン？
Fans?
It's a religious group called Psycho Helmet.
（米里）
サイコヘルメット教っていう
宗教団体
Oh, it's a religious group.
宗教団体か
We're looking for our god.
Psycho Helmet Religion
Oh, it's that.
あれか
During the press conference the other day...
この間の記者会見のときに
Apparently, there was a split-second shot
of you from behind.
モブ君の後ろ姿が
一瞬 カメラに映ってたみたいで
They analyzed the footage
映像解析して
制服から塩(しお)中学校が特定されたの
and found out that your uniform
was from Salt Middle School.
The followers are positive that
the poltergeist incident wasn't a fake.
あのポルターガイスト現象は
フェイクじゃないって
教団の人たちは確信している
They're likely going to come observe
the area on the day of the marathon.
恐らく マラソン大会当日に
視察に来るわ
That's when you'll reveal that
you're the leader they've been looking for!
そこで自分たちの教祖の正体が
モブ君だって発覚するのよ！
そういう
大事な瞬間は―
Don't you want to make that
important moment as dramatic as possible?
劇的なものに
したくない？
Sorry, but I'm going to run
using my own physical strength.
悪いけど 僕は自力で走るよ
I'm even jogging now,
今はランニングしてるし
so maybe by next year I'll be able
to place within the top ten.
来年なら 頑張れば10位以内に
入賞できるかもしれないし
Wow... You actually thought
about it that much?
へえ～
お前 そこまで意識してたんだ？
Who knew you actually had a goal?
ちゃんと目標を立ててたとは…
ら… 来年じゃダメなの！
It can't be next year!
We'll have our high school
entrance exams next year!
来年は私たち受験生でしょ？
We won't have time to deal
with stuff like this anymore!
そんなゴタゴタに構う余裕
なくなっちゃうのよ！
That's right. Oh, no...
そうだった　しまった！
どうした？
What's up?
If I placed in the top ten
of next year's marathon,
来年のマラソン大会で入賞したら
I was planning on asking
Tsubomi-chan out...
ツボミちゃんに告白しようと
思ってたのに
S-Say what?
な… なんだと！
え？　高嶺(たかね)さんに？
What? Takane-san?!
生徒会選挙じゃ
失敗しちゃったけど
I messed up during the student
council president election,
but I wanted to show her how cool
I could be at next year's marathon.
来年のマラソン大会で
いいとこ
見せたかったんだ
Shigeo...
（エクボ）
茂夫 お前 俺様にも気付かれずに
いつの間にそこまで…
How were you able to change
so much without my noticing?
If next year doesn't work,
it'll have to be this year.
（モブ）
来年がダメなら今年だ
I'll just have to place in the top ten
in the marathon next week!
来週のマラソン大会で
10位以内に入るしかない！
Telepathy Club
Body Improvement Club
No way! That's the last thing
I thought I'd hear you say.
無理 無理！
何を言いだすかと思えば
Do you even remember
where you finished last year?
（暗田(くらた)トメ）
あんた 去年の順位 覚えてる？
２９１位
291st...
遅い！
You're way too slow!
Strengthening month!!
You finished in the bottom ten.
後ろから10位に入賞してんじゃん
How are you going to remedy
that in just ten days?
残り10日で
どう対策しようっていうのよ？
Monthly
Muscle
Five kilometers is a pretty
rough distance, too.
５キロは
なかなか厳しい距離だしなあ
（猿田(さるた)）
あっ 俺の兄貴
高校で陸上やってるんで
My older brother does track in high school.
Should I ask him for some tips?
コツとか聞いときましょうか？
Last-minute advice isn't going to
turn him into a speedster!
付け焼き刃のアドバイスで
なんとかなるレベルじゃないでしょ
Maybe watch what you eat
and tone your body a bit...
（雉子林(きじばやし)）
食事メニュー 気をつけて
少しでも体を調整するとか
いや
ダイエットじゃないんだから！
We're not talking about a diet here!
あっ そうだ！
Oh, I know. Why not buy
some fancy running shoes?
ちょっといいランニングシューズ
買うとか
You think he has that kind of money?
そんなお金 ある？
I'll have to give it my all...
頑張るしかない
That's exactly right, Kageyama!
（鬼瓦天牙(おにがわらてんが)）
そのとおりだ 影山！
That's why you're our shadow leader!
それでこそ裏番だ
The methods and their efficiency don't matter!
方法とか効率とかは関係ねえ
What matters is whether
you wanna do this or not!
本当に肝心なのは
やるか やらねえかだ
Monthly Muscle
You understand that!
お前は それを
よく分かってるじゃねえか
Put on muscle
However, Kageyama...
だがな 影山
Put on muscle
Giving something your all ain't easy.
“頑張る”ってのは
そう なまやさしい言葉じゃねえ！
Put on muscle
Do you have what it takes
to really put everything on the line?
お前に 本当に
頑張るだけの覚悟はあるのか？
I... I do.
あ… あります
Then you can have my running shoes.
俺のランシュー やる
What? But they're brand new!
え？　それ 新品なのに…
You're just going to give them to Mob?
モブにあげちゃうんですか？
But why, Onigawara-senpai?
（モブ）
鬼瓦先輩 どうして？
フッ せいぜい気張れよ
You better do this thing.
He's so cool...
かっこいい
Oh, those!
（郷田(ごうだ)武蔵(むさし)）
おお それ
So you ended up with them, Kageyama!
影山が もらったのか
鬼瓦がサイズ間違えて買った靴
The shoes Onigawara bought in the wrong size!
Did you have to open your big mouth?
（暗田）
言わなくていいのに…
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Why are you so fidgety, Mob?
（霊幻新隆(れいげんあらたか)）
なにソワソワしてんだよ モブ？
Reception
Oh, I'm just trying to exercise
any chance I get.
（モブ）
あっ いや 空いた時間で
少しでも運動しようと思って
Oh, so you're not fidgeting.
（霊幻）
貧乏揺すりじゃないのか
He's got a marathon coming up.
（エクボ）
あいつ マラソン大会が近いんだよ
A marathon, huh?
マラソン大会か
I always acted like I was sick.
俺はよく仮病 使ってたな～
He's gonna try to place in the top ten
10位以内に入って
and tell his beloved Tsubomi-chan how he feels.
意中のツボミちゃんに
告白するんだと
You're going to ask her out? Seriously?
告白って… マジか お前？
If you have
3 evil spirits,
the exorcism
fee on 1 of
them will be
on the house!!
You don't have to come to work for a while.
お前
しばらくバイト 来なくていいぞ
Huh? But why?
え？　どうしてですか？
（霊幻）
どうせ当分 客も来ないし…
I'm probably not getting
any customers for a while anyway.
More importantly, you should be
jogging to better prepare your body.
それより ジョギングとかして
慣らしたほうがいいな
All right, get changed.
（霊幻）よし 着替えろ
（モブ）え？
Huh?
We're going to get your legs accustomed
to the actual course you'll be running.
本番と同じコースを
脚に覚えさせるんだ
Come on, lift those feet, Reigen!
（エクボ）
おら！　足 上げろ 霊幻！
Shut up!
（霊幻）
うるせえ！
I haven't... been exercising...
that much lately... myself!
俺だって ここんところ
運動不足だったんだよ！
I can't hear you!
（エクボ）
声 出せ！　声！
（霊幻）
そこで 一旦 お茶するか？
Hey, want to stop for some tea?
But we've only run about a
kilometer so far, Master.
（モブ）
まだ１キロぐらいですよ 師匠
Huh? Nii-san?
（律）
あれ？　兄さん？
Hey, Ritsu.
よっ 律じゃねえか
Dimple? Is he training for the marathon?
（律）
エクボ マラソン大会の練習？
Yeah.
ああ　10位以内に入って
ツボミちゃんに告白するんだとよ
Apparently, he's going to place in the
top ten and ask Tsubomi-chan out.
What?!
Takane Tsubomi-san?
（律）
高嶺ツボミさんか
I remember playing with her
when we were younger,
小さいころ 一緒に
遊んでもらったことがあるけど
but honestly, I found her
kind of hard to deal with.
実は ちょっと苦手なタイプだ
I'm pretty sure I remember her going home
in the middle of hide-and-seek...
かくれんぼの途中で
帰っちゃうような人だった気が…
This makes me uneasy.
不安だ
I wonder if Nii-san will be okay...
大丈夫かな 兄さん
Shige! Wash your own dishes, will you?
（モブの母）
シゲ 自分の食器 洗いなさいよ！
Shige!
シゲ！
It's okay, Mom.
（律）
いいよ 母さん　僕がやるよ
I'll do it.
You don't have to, Ritsu. You shouldn't
spoil your older brother like that.
いいのよ 律
お兄ちゃん甘やかしちゃダメよ
Is something up?
どうかしたのか？
兄さん 頑張ってるみたいだから
Nii-san's working really hard lately,
so I don't mind helping him just a bit.
その間だけでも
兄さんの分ぐらい やるよ
Remember to take
2 breaths at once
Breathe in deeply, breathe out deeply
6-beat breathing style
Vertical
Stride
Longer strides
More damage
Faster speed, stamina...
Cadence
More rotations
Less damage
Uses more stamina
Oh, hey, you two.
Thanks for coming by today.
（霊幻）
おう お前ら 助かったぜ
I look forward to working with you guys.
今日は よろしくな
I'm just doing this for my brother.
兄さんのためですよ
練習に集中してもらいたいので
I want him to be able to
concentrate on training.
That said, we are subbing in for Kageyama-kun.
（テル）
とはいえ 影山君の代理だからね
I'll make sure I put my time in.
しっかり働きますよ
じゃあ まず その資料まとめて
Then, first, could you sort those files?
Also, take a look at any
exorcism request emails.
除霊依頼のメールにも
目を通しといてくれ
Hello? Are you open?
（ミキ）
あの… やってますか？
I didn't make a reservation or anything.
予約してないんですけど
Oh, I can see you immediately.
（霊幻）
ああ 今ならすぐ
Please, have a seat.
どうぞ お座りください
All right, go get some tea ready—
よし じゃあ早速 お茶をお出しして
Where'd the other kid go?
あれ？　あいつは？
He seems to be hiding for some reason.
なんでか隠れました
Takane-san?!
（律）
高嶺さん なぜ ここに？
What is she doing here?
I don't care about myself,
僕はともかく
兄さんが こんなうさんくさい店と
つながりがあるなんて
but I can't let her find out Nii-san has
ties with a shady place like this.
悟られるわけには いかない！
Um, I heard that you also
give relationship advice...
あの… 恋愛相談もやってるって
聞いてきたんですけど　ね？
Right?
Yeah.
（ツボミ）
うん　お願いできますか？
Could you do that for us?
Relationship advice?!
（律）
恋愛相談？
If I could have you fill out
this questionnaire first.
（霊幻）
では まずアンケート用紙に記入を
Oh, sure.
あっ はい
（霊幻）
ふむふむ なるほど
I see. So you go to Salt Middle School.
塩中の生徒さんですか
I actually know someone
at Salt Middle School.
私も塩中には
知り合いがいるんですよ
Reigen! You shut your mouth!
（律）
霊幻 余計なこと 言うんじゃない！
With our satisfied
customers
What's this person like, Miki-chan?
ミキちゃん
相手は どんな子なんだい？
Spirits and Such Consultation Office
Uh, could you let me do my job, please?
（霊幻）
いや 俺の仕事まで
奪わないでくれるかな
I see...
So this person is probably in your grade,
or maybe a bit older...
そうなると相手は
恐らく 同級生 もしくは先輩
And they play some kind of sport.
何かスポーツをやっていて…
Wow! You're right!
（ミキ）
すごい　当たってる！
う～ん なるほど
I see.
He's on the soccer team,
so you want to get him some cleats.
サッカー部だからスパイクを
プレゼントしようと思ってるのか
でも あまり高価な物だと
But if you get him a really nice pair,
気持ちより先に金銭的な
価値 印象が先行してしまうし
their monetary value may leave
a bigger impression than your feelings.
With our satisfied
customers
In that case, I think you
should start off as friends.
それなら まず
友人関係から初めて…
Ask him what his hobbies
are outside of soccer,
例えば部活以外では
何をしているのかとか…
or about his favorite TV show...
So basically,
…というわけで
there's no need for you to rush in
and ask him out, Miki-san.
ミキさんは なにも焦って
いきなり告白する必要はないと
In my opinion, at least.
私は思います
Okay! Thank you so much!
はい ありがとうございます
That was really helpful!
すごく参考になりました
Um, I didn't fill out the questionnaire,
but can I ask you some questions, too?
あの
アンケート 書いてないんですけど
私も相談 いいですか？
Yes, of course!
ええ もちろん
あなたも恋愛に関する？
Did you want relationship advice as well?
Yes. The person I like is someone from
another school who I meet at cram school.
はい　好きな相手は
塾で会う他校の子なんですけど
Ah, I see.
（霊幻）
ほう なるほど なるほど
They talk to me all the time.
（ツボミ）
よく話しかけてくれるんです
Hey, what's with you, man?
さっきから どうしたの？
で 塾の帰りとかに
一緒になったりもするんですけど
Sometimes, we even walk home
together after cram school.
Should I ask them out?
告白すべきでしょうか？
（霊幻）
ふ～む 確かにそのケースなら
Well, in that case, I think it'd be
fine to ask them out immediately.
すぐにでも
告白してもいいかもしれませんね
Hey!
（律）
おい！
With our satisfied
customers
From what you've told me, the other person
is obviously interested in you as well.
話を聞いた感触だと
相手も あなたが
気になっているのは間違いない
If you ask them out, there's a very
good possibility they'll say yes.
告白すれば
十中八九 うまくいくはずです
It's over...
（律）
終わった
Okay.
（ツボミ）
分かりました
Thank you very much.
（２人）
ありがとうございました
Please come by again anytime.
また いつでもどうぞ～
Do you know them, Little Bro?
弟君の知り合い？
やけに大人びてたね
They looked older.
Well, uh...
いや まあ
I can't...
（律）
言えない 兄さんには…
I can't tell Nii-san.
You can do this, Nii-san!
頑張れ 兄さん！
ハア ハア…
I didn't know you went to
cram school, Tsubomi.
（ミキ）
ツボミ 塾なんて通ってたの？
初耳なんだけど
You never mentioned that before.
Nope. I just made it up.
ううん
適当に話 合わせてただけだよ
I didn't want you to get
scammed or something,
ミキが詐欺とかにダマされたら
嫌だから
so I thought I'd test him a little.
試してみようと思って
Oh, really? I see.
ええ？　なんだ そういうことか
And what did you think, Tsubomi?
それで
ツボミとしては どうだったの？
う～ん そうだな
Well...
He didn't say anything wrong...
So he's probably okay.
間違ったことは言ってなかったし
まっ 大丈夫か
Mob Psycho
The Day of the Marathon
Salt Middle School Marathon
You can do it!
頑張れ～！
My parents are here.
うちの親 来てるわ
Who's the fastest out of the guys?
男子 誰が速いの？
This day has finally arrived.
（米里）
ついに この日が来た
There are followers waiting
near the finish line.
ゴール付近では
教団の関係者たちが待ち構えている
It's time to present their beloved leader.
いよいよ教祖様のお披露目ね
You've got this, Mob-kun!
頑張ってね モブ君！
I'm sure Ritsu will be fine,
but I'm a bit worried about Shigeo.
まあ 律はともかく 茂夫は心配だな
Yeah. He's got the stamina of a snail.
そうね　体力 あれだし…
We should watch from somewhere along
the course rather than the finish line.
ゴール付近より中間地点まで
見に行きましょう
Nurse's Station
Salt MS
Cough, cough.
（雉子林）
ゴホッ ゴホッ
Oh, no. I've caught a cold.
いや～
風邪をひいてしまった　残念
Hack, hack.
Visitor Station
（犬川）
ケホ ケホッ
Oh, did you catch a cold too, Kijibayashi-san?
あれ？　雉子林さんも風邪ですか？
So did I!
俺もですよ
Wow, that's such a coincidence, Inukawa.
（雉子林）
犬川！　奇遇ですな
Horf, horf. Horf...
（猿田）
ウホッ ウホッ
You, too, Saruta? Not bad for a first-year.
（雉子林）
猿田もかよ
１年のくせに なかなかやるな
Oh, you're too kind.
（猿田）
いやいや 恐縮です
I learned a lot from the Telepathy Club.
脳電部で
いろいろと鍛えられましたから
Run, you lazy bastards!
走りなさい あんたたち！
Salt MS
Inukawa
Kijibayashi
Salt MS
Saruta
Even Mob-kun's going to run!
モブ君が走ろうとしてるんだから！
So you three better get going, too!
ほら あんたたちも！
Shigeo! How ya doin'?
（エクボ）
茂夫 調子はどうよ？
あ… ダメだ こいつ
He's doomed. He's super nervous.
メチャクチャ緊張してやがる
Shape up, Kageyama!
シャキッとしろ 影山！
（モブ）
部長
President.
Show everyone the fruits of your training!
思いきり
特訓の成果をぶつけてこい！
We're rivals today!
今日はライバルだからな
Rivals...
（モブ）
ライバル
I'll do my best!
（モブ）頑張ります！
（鬼瓦）お？
（鬼瓦）
ヘッ
随分と履き込んできたじゃねえか
Looks like he put those to good use.
Way to go, shadow leader.
さすがは裏番だな
We will now begin the boys' race of
the Salt Middle School Marathon.
（体育教師）
よ～し これより
Salt Middle School Marathon
塩中マラソン 男子の部
スタートする！
On your marks...
（体育教師）
位置について ヨ～イ…
Ready...
Nii-san!
（律）
兄さん！
Salt Middle School
（モブ）
ハア ハア ハア
You're not catching up to
the leading pack on that leg...
（エクボ）
その足じゃ 先頭集団には…
Want me to possess you?
乗り移ってやろうか？
You just need to make the top ten, right?
10位以内になれば いいんだろ？
Figures.
だよな
My kid looked so annoyed.
（親）
うちの子
面倒くさそうに走ってたわ
There's no way they'll catch up to the front.
（親）
前の方には追いつけないわよね
Ritsu passed by a long time ago.
律は とっくに
走り抜けていったが…
シゲ！
Shige!
What happened to your leg?!
その足 どうしたの？
But you built up your stamina, right?
でも あんた
体力ついたんじゃないの？
Hang in there!
ファイト ファイト！
You're doing amazing!
You can do this, Shigeo!
すごいぞ！　頑張れ 茂夫！
Our boy has real guts now.
あの子 根性ついたわ
Yeah.
I should make something yummy
for dinner tonight.
今日は おいしいものを
作っておかなくちゃ
（ツボミ）
あっ モブ君
Mob-kun.
You can d—
ガンバ！
（モブ）
ハア ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
His form's all wrong.
（エクボ）
走り方 おかしいな
Did he sprain something?
くじいたのかもな
His pace is getting erratic, too.
ペースも乱れてきた
Hey, you've only got
about a kilometer to go.
（霊幻）
おい あと１キロちょっとだぞ！
Move them legs!
足 動かせ！
Reigen, you look like you're going all out.
霊幻 本気のスタイルだな
見るな
Don't look.
I thought I'd help him keep
his pace toward the end,
ラストスパートのペースメーカーに
なってやろうと思ってたんだが…
but the guys up front are way too fast.
トップ争いの連中が速すぎる
They're way ahead.
だいぶ 差をつけられたから
I don't know if we can catch up
even if you sprint.
全力疾走しても追いつけるかどうか
ハア ハア ハア…
カウントしてたんだが 現在74位
I've been counting runners.
You're currently 74th.
That's fantastic for Mob,
モブにしちゃ大健闘だが
but for him to finish in the top ten,
he has to pass 64 others.
入賞するには
あと64人 抜かす必要がある
なるほど
I see...
Wanna get a taxi?
タクシー 拾うか？
I mean, the thought did cross my mind...
（霊幻）
まあ それもちょっと考えたけど…
Don't be ridiculous. Look at that face.
バカ言え　見ろよ あの顔
きっと まだ諦めてないんだ
I'm pretty sure he hasn't given up yet.
ハア ハア ハア ハア…
ああっ ハア ハア
Kageyama, you're awake?
（古賀）
影山 目が覚めたか？
You should never push yourself too far.
何事も無理は いかんぞ
Sensei...
（モブ）
先生
That marathon's over, huh?
終わったんですね マラソン大会
Yeah...
Oh, your younger brother managed to
overtake some third-years and place 9th.
お前の弟 ３年生を抜かして
９位入賞だったぞ
I see.
そうですか 律が
Ritsu...
Kageyama, you used to seem a bit glum,
影山
前は もう少し
暗いイメージだったけど
but you're much brighter now.
いい顔 するようになったな
はい？
Pardon?
Do you need someone to come get you?
（古賀）
迎えに来てもらうか？
No, I can go home myself.
（モブ）
いえ １人で帰れます
He hasn't shown up...
（信者）
来ませんね
Yeah... Where in the world is our leader?
（信者）
ああ　教祖様は 一体どこに…
Well, you're in a good mood.
ご機嫌だな
Of course I am.
そりゃ 喜んでるわよ
We're celebrating Ritsu placing 9th,
and Shige running the whole nine.
律が９番！
シゲは 限界まで走ったで賞！
What the heck?
（父）
何だ そりゃ？　ハハハハハッ
I'll get it. I wonder if it's Nii-san.
出るよ　兄さんかな？
Koga-sensei just called saying
he left school a little while ago.
（母）
さっき 古賀先生から
学校 出たって電話があったわ
I'm glad he just had mild anemia.
（律）
一時的な貧血でよかったよ
（ショウ）
よお！
Heya.
お前は
You're...
あのときの…
the one from...
How did you find this place?
どうして ここが？
Didn't I say I'd be seeing you again?
“また会おう”って
言わなかったっけ？
Who is it? A friend of yours?
（母）
誰？　お友達？
（律）
母さん！
Mom!
Don't come over here right now!
今 こっちに来ないで！
Oh... Now I see.
あ～あ そっか そっか
親もいるんだ？
Your parents are here, too.
I guess I shouldn't be surprised.
そりゃそうか　これは面倒だな
Well, this complicates things.
Hey, what do you mean by—
おい それはどういう…
What is that?
何だ あれ？
I wonder what's going on.
There's smoke over there.
何だろう？　あっちで煙が…
火事か？
Is there a fire?
Wait...
って おい
Isn't that where...
あの方角って…
Apparently, there was
a sudden explosion of fire.
（住民１）
急に爆発するように
火が出たんですって
They said it might've been an arsonist.
（住民２）放火かもって
（モブ）ああ…
Nobody knows if the family got to safety.
逃げ出したところは
確認できてないそうよ
Oh, you're one of the Kageyama boys.
（住民１）
あっ 影山さんとこの…
Thank goodness you're safe.
よかった　無事だったのね
（住民２）
えっ ちょっと！　落ち着いて！
H-Hey, wait! Pull yourself together!
You can't go any closer!
（住民１）
近づいちゃダメよ！
Someone, please stop him!
（住民２）
ちょっと あの子 誰か止めて！
（住民たち）
キャー！　大変！
火の中に入っていっちゃった！
That's dangerous!
He went into the fire!
It's okay... Dad was home today.
（モブ）
大丈夫
今日は お父さんが
家にいたんだから
Dad can be a bit strict at times,
お父さんは たまに厳しいけど
強くて頼りになるんだ
but he's strong and reliable.
He even took the day off from
work today to watch me run.
会社まで休んで
僕のマラソン 見に来てくれたんだ
And Mom's always careful with the stove.
お母さんだって
火の扱いには いつも注意してた
When I was younger, she yelled at me
for messing around with fireworks.
小さいころに
花火でふざけて すごく怒られた
それに 律がいるんだ
Not to mention, Ritsu's here.
いつでも冷静で優秀な弟
He's my brilliant younger brother
who's always calm.
It's okay. It'll be okay.
大丈夫 大丈夫だよ
It's too bad that our home is burning down,
家が燃えたのは残念だけど
みんながいれば やり直せるんだ
but as long as we're together,
we can start over.
There's no one here?
誰もいない
They must've gotten away, then!
やっぱり うまく逃げたんだ
Shigeo!
（エクボ）
茂夫！
There were signs of a struggle
at the front door.
玄関に争った形跡があった
Someone must've forced their way in!
誰かが乗り込んできやがったんだ！
Someone did this...?
誰かが これをやったのか？
ちょ… ちょっと待って
H-Hang on a sec.
じゃあ ３人は
連れ去られた可能性もあるんじゃ…
Does that mean someone
could've taken them, too?
I have to look for clues!
何か手がかりを探さなくちゃ！
Close your eyes!
目を閉じろ！
Don't look, Shigeo!
それを見るな 茂夫！
I spilled a seed and lost sight of it
I'll find it using the color it's dyed in and watch it grow
It immediately returned to the palm of my hand
But it's still too light and too frail to reach for the skies
The world coldly drains away all the heat
The bright sunshine just isn't enough
The memories are closing off what lies ahead
Shake off their warmth and set off into the distance
If I let it wither, it'd be over just like that
But my hope just doesn't fade away
The super dangerous esper organization,
Claw, attacks Seasoning City!
（霊幻）
超危険な超能力組織“爪”が
調味市(ちょうみし)に攻め込んできた
ボスに幹部に外人部隊
The boss, the upper echelon,
and the foreigner squad...
It appears that I, Reigen Arataka,
must make a stand!
こうなったら この霊幻新隆が
立ち上がるしかないようだな
Next time on Mob Psycho 100 II Episode 9:
次回「モブサイコ100 Ⅱ」
第９話“見せてみろ　集合”
"Show Me What You've Got ~Band Together~."
Illegal downloads?
Do you want to be cursed?
Show Me What You've Got
~Band Together~
違法ダウンロード？
あなた 呪われますよ